the NordicTrack commercial x-22i might
be the most versatile treadmill on the
market it has a 40 incline a top speed
of 12 miles per hour and an extremely
unique sled push feature but is it worth
the 3 500 price tag stick around and
we'll find out
[Music]
what's up everybody it's Jake coming at
you from the barbing garage gym with
another review this time around we're
rolling with the NordicTrack commercial
x-22i treadmill if you don't know how
this whole process works in this video
today I'm going to tell you a lot of
things but specifically we're going to
go over some money over some pros and
cons some of the features this treadmill
offers but most importantly who should
or maybe shouldn't make this purchase
now before I do all of that got to let
you know that we've reviewed a ton of
treadmills on barbin.com and we went
ahead and made a best list of all of our
top choices so if you want to check that
out which definitely think you should
all you got to do is search bar band
best treadmills that list is going to
pull right up for you and you can find
out for yourself which ones we like the
best
[Music]
all right so as I mentioned this very
well might be the most versatile
treadmill on the market so it has a 40
incline which you know aside from its
sibling I guess you could call it the
x-32i this is the highest available
incline on the market it also has a
negative six degree decline so that way
you can kind of add in some Hill work
you know with all of your workouts but
you can also Sprint with it since it
does have a max speed of 12 miles per
hour one more thing about that is that
the rollers here on this treadmill are
2.5 inches in diameter that is perfect
for anybody who's a dedicated long
distance Runner or a sprinter you know
if you don't already know rollers are
very responsible for the actual belt of
the treadmill you know that's what's
turning the belt and also again keeping
it up to speed with the motor and the
bigger they are you know the less they
have to work and you know the longer
they're going to last so 2.5 inches
that's perfect for anybody who's a
runner now you also have a 4.0 CHP motor
with this treadmill right here which
that is really beefy so CHP stands for
constant horsepower you know you'll see
on some lower end treadmills it's just
HP that's basically just talking about
that Peak Performance so CHP it's always
going to be performing you know at its
Max Capacity all right now
kind of expanding off the versatility
here is the sled push feature I love
this right here it's super unique and
basically what this is is you're going
to go to the manual setting you know on
this treadmill and basically you just
start pushing the belt is going to be on
one mile per hour basically you just
grab onto the handlebars and you're
responsible with your own leg drive to
you know keep that belt moving so this
is a great posterior chain workout for
somebody who wants to you know really
strengthen your legs that's going to be
really really sweet for you right there
now similar to the rest of nordictracks
gear you know you do have access to iFit
on the 22 inch touchscreen monitor right
there it's going to be really sweet now
during those iFit classes you're going
to experience automatic adjustments to
your incline Decline and your speed
settings now you can always override
those but I think that's really cool and
it's going to prevent you from really
just becoming complacent during your
workouts and you have your trainer kind
of controlling everything and really
pushing you another really cool thing
here is the reflex Kush all right so
basically just to summarize the amount
of cushion you're going to receive from
this treadmill is directly correlated to
your body mass all right so if you're
somebody who's you know smaller framed
you're gonna experience less cushioning
than somebody who's bigger frame
basically that makes sense now
regardless of your body type it's going
to basically be perfect in that sweet
spot like Goldilocks and Three Bears
porridge it's going to be basically
perfect on your joints now
take a deep breath all these things
being said there's still some things you
might want to know about you probably
should know about you might not be too
crazy about the first thing is how
massive this treadmill is it's huge
remember 40 incline you got to make sure
you have enough Headroom so we have
about eight foot tall ceilings in here
and my head gets pretty close I'll show
you on a little bit my head gets pretty
close to the rafters up here and that's
not the most ideal thing in the world
for everybody so keep that in mind
another thing here is that this is a
very pricey treadmill I'm gonna break it
all down in just a second but starting
price tag of this treadmill is right
around thirty five hundred dollars so
that's not in your budget
I suggest looking elsewhere and on top
of that you're gonna have to pay whether
it be monthly or one of the three yearly
plans I'll break down you have to pay
for your iFit membership if you do
monthly it's about 40 bucks a month now
on top of that expensive purchase that
might not be the most ideal thing in the
world but it's gonna be worth it you
know it's really how you're getting the
most out of this treadmill so definitely
keep that in mind another thing here is
that there are not any pulse sensors on
the handlebars that's kind of a bummer
to me you know you'd kind of expect a
treadmill with a price tag like this and
kind of how nice this treadmill is that
you would have pulse sensors that way
you don't have to you don't already have
one you know make an additional purchase
just for a heart rate monitor to get an
accurate reading on your burned calories
and your actual heart rate in addition
to it being you know a behemoth of a
treadmill it also doesn't folds that
deck does not fold and while it does
have you know a set of wheels to help
you move it around this thing also
weighs over 400 pounds so it's kind of
difficult to move it I would definitely
suggest just keeping it in one spot
another thing here is that the actual
console itself you know it's pretty big
you know obviously you have that 22 inch
touchscreen monitor but on either side
of it where all your controls and
everything are that sticks out pretty
far so while you do have two cup holders
and two phone holders it's kind of
difficult to reach that at certain times
so kind of remember that right there and
then another thing here is that the
silver framework I guess you want to
call it behind me right here that's you
know straddles the treadmill it kind of
prevents you from you know getting the
most out of that 60 inch deck so I'll
I'll explain this in further detail but
you know compared to the x32i you have
less leg room these are almost identical
treadmills but so with this right here
where that's positioned if you're
somebody who's over six feet tall you
might have a hard time when it's you
know fully flat for you to really you
know reach your stride length and really
just stretch out
all right
okay so once again the NordicTrack
commercial x22i it's going to run you
right around 3 500 that original price
tag should I say there's additional
variables to where you could potentially
spend up to about fifty two hundred
dollars on this one piece of equipment
now first of all we gotta talk about
iFit all right so if you just want to
pay monthly for your membership it's
about 40 bucks a month 39 40 bucks
whatever you want to call it about 40
bucks a month now you want to save money
long term going after one of the three
different yearly plans is definitely the
way to go so that one year plan is about
400 bucks to your plan is about 700 and
the three year plan is about nine
hundred dollars now yes that adds a
significant amount of money up front but
that three-year plan saves you about 500
and the two-year plan saves about 270 or
something roughly like that and that one
your plan is Gonna Save you about 70
bucks so really that three year plan is
where you're saving the most in the long
run it comes with a 10-year warranty on
the framework but you know if you want
an extended plan it's about 300 bucks
there's also an extra ended maintenance
plan you can add on about 450 bucks
three year plan and you know during that
time frame somebody's gonna come out do
a 15 Point checklist on your treadmill
just make sure it's performing at its
peak you know performance and that's a
really good thing in my opinion I think
it's worth that money because I would
imagine most of y'all aren't sitting
there doing all the checks and
everything to make sure that this is
performing as it should so might be
worth spending that money now this is
obviously a big old chunk of change
right there right now it's hard to
compare this treadmill to all the other
treadmills on the market because it's so
unique now the only one that's really
similar to it is once again it's sibling
I guess you don't want to call it the
x32i
it's a thousand dollars more it's about
forty four hundred dollars original
price tag and really the only thing
different is you have a 32 inch
touchscreen monitor rather than 22
inches and the steel framework I was
talking about is at the end of the
actual treadmill so you actually do get
a little bit more legroom mainly if
you're you know over six feet tall so
that might be worth it but it's a
thousand dollars more now let's just
kind of stick with the NordicTrack
family okay so the 2450 is a really
solid treadmill as well it's about three
thousand dollars and since there's way
more versatility with the x22i I think
this is
worth it or more worth it than the 2450.
now another good one is the 1750. about
2500 bucks and it basically has all the
exact same specs as the 2450. and it's
about 500 cheaper so that's a good one
right there and if you just want to
stick with NordicTrack but maybe you
don't need all these you know fancy
features one that is still pretty nice
and it does have you know pretty much
all the same modern conveniences it just
doesn't have decline as high of an
incline or as high of a top speed is the
EXP 7i which is about 1300 bucks so
all in all I mean y'all basically
you're getting what you're paying for
right here you know you got a 4.0 CHP
motor 2.5 inch rollers you can do any
type of cardio workout you can imagine
basically you know with this treadmill
so yeah it's expensive but it's going to
be worth it in the long run
[Music]
all right so I just want to reiterate on
a couple things here but before I'll do
that I didn't mention this you do have a
steel framework right here this toss of
a treadmill is not moving it is
417 pounds it is a beast it's not like I
said it's just simply not gonna move but
you do have a set of wheels so once you
kind of get it up there you are able to
move it around it's just a little bit
difficult to get to that point remember
you do have 2.5 inch rollers which is
perfect for runners and you do have that
4.0 CHP motor so it is also a beast of a
motor and it's going to be able to give
you a grueling workout and be able to
run for you know an extended period of
time and allow you to run at an extended
period of time now once again you do
have that 22 inch touchscreen monitor
and you're going to have automatic
adjustments during those iFit classes
but on either side of that monitor you
do have buttons that will allow you to
manually adjust you know you can press
that eight mile per hour speed gonna
jump right to eight miles per hour but
if you double tap it I'm gonna go to 8.8
and then you know if you double actually
not double tap excuse me if you just
press you know 20 incline it's going to
go straight to it and honestly because
this motor is as strong as it is those
adjustments happen relatively quick you
know in the grand scheme of things yes
you are going to have a tiny bit of
downtime but compared to other
treadmills on the market that's you know
pretty mini School in my opinion but to
me the biggest and best feature of all
about this treadmill is hands down that
sled push mode and I'm going to show you
here in just a second but I think that's
perfect for anybody who wants to really
strengthen their legs you're just using
your own body your own leg drive to push
literally you're pushing you know this
belt and causing it to move which is
just awesome
all right so with this treadmill
remember you doesn't fold the deck does
not fold but you do have a handlebar
down here that's going to help it you
know be at least a little bit easier for
you to lift it up and move it around
your personal space regarding the actual
deck though remember it measures 60
inches in length 22 inches wide which is
pretty much the sweet spot for a solid
treadmill only thing here is that
because of where you know this framework
is positioned if you're somebody over
six feet tall you might have some
difficulties when it's flat like this
you know really hitting your full stride
you're either going to have to you know
run from a little bit further back on
the deck or just try to do your best to
make it happen with this remember with
the x32i all of this is actually
positioned at the front or the back
whatever whichever way you want to refer
to it right that's something you should
keep in mind now
this is almost like a spaceship up here
I mean this is massive now look you do
have you know your phone holder right
here and cup holder right there I got my
phone sometimes it's a little difficult
you kind of got to go up here and then
slide it down and then get you know
funky with it with your water bottle so
you know just something you're going to
have to deal with all right now you do
have a fan right here two fans actually
that rotate a little bit and they are
gonna really help cool you off when
you're working out which is pretty cool
now
there's so much right here from iFit
this does not tilt or anything like a
lot of the other ones pretty much all
the other ones do so that's something
you should keep in mind but it is angled
so it's not like you're really gonna
have to Crane your neck when you're
working out so
I fit you know there's so many classes
available it's kind of ridiculous while
you can't necessarily stream those
additional classes from here like you
can with the 2450 1750 all the other
ones that rotate and everything you can
download the companion app on your phone
or your tablet and stream all the
classes from there and every workout you
do will get uploaded to here because
it's one profile and vice versa and
speaking of profiles you can have five
total so four additional including your
own that's pretty cool too and
everybody's gonna have their own
homepage your own past seven days of
working out really trophy case what's
your trophy case so for example there's
a welcome to iFit challenge there's road
to recovery you know 20 workouts 21 20.
once you complete those you will get a
trophy it's going to a little trophy
case right here and that's just kind of
cool you get achievements which we all
like that now go to browse it's going to
have you know even more to choose from
it's got like full catalog of classes
right here you can search by title
trainer or workout type which is really
cool there's a lot of different filters
but really what is my favorite thing
I've talked about this in all these
Nordic Track videos
is the create option so Google Maps is
completely integrated right here
so I just clicked on create took us to
London so we can literally take a second
for it to buffer now but we can
literally pick anywhere we want right
here and make our own track our own
course whatever you want to call it and
because Google Maps is fully integrated
there's going to be automatic
adjustments to the deck you know incline
decline based off of the lay of the land
and you're gonna get the Google camera
street view which is pretty cool too now
I don't want to bore you to death by
making you you know watch me join a
class and do the warm-up and everything
like that so let's just go to the manual
start
and this is gonna be really cool too
because first thing I'm going to do is
I'm just going to show you guys how to
do the sled push since it's pretty
straightforward right so once it starts
going one mile per hour so basically
just go and hit end warm up basically
all you do is you grab all of these
handlebars right here you could do
whatever but I like doing these and you
just sit here and you just drive your
legs and
it's not assisting you whatsoever so
this is all on you this is a great way
to really strengthen those glutes and
hammies and even your calves your whole
posterior chain it's really cool now
I mentioned it you know responds pretty
quick I'm gonna step off really quick so
I don't get hurt we're gonna click 12
miles per hour
and that's getting up there really fast
that's up there really quick now it is a
little loud
12 miles per hour though I mean it is
what it is right that's really
responsive and also talk about that
double tap feature so we're gonna go
three three right here
and then boom it's already dropping down
really quick and it's natural you know
it's not just a sudden change so it
allows your body to slowly slow down or
actually you know speed up which is cool
now
let me put this on one
we're gonna put this on 40 to 40 percent
all right wait one second you can
probably already see these beams right
here
but
as we go up and this is honestly pretty
quick too compared to a lot of other
treadmills out there that's because it
does have that 4.0 CHP motor so it's you
know constant horsepower it's really
strong and this is another great way to
really build that posterior chain within
your cardio workouts and we're still
growing we're still climbing a little
bit right here there it is and look
these are right around right around
eight feet right here and my head is and
I barely have enough clearance right
here to get a workout in so if you don't
have you know ceilings this high or
taller this really isn't going to work
for you all right now let me get back
down here
go ahead and get back down to zero
there's so many great things about this
treadmill yes it's really big yes it's
really expensive but you know just this
crash course of features I just gave you
I think makes it worth it so if you're
looking for the most versatile treadmill
on the market
I think you found it it's right here
behind me you know there's a whole lot
you can do with it and that's great for
various reasons you know you have that
40 incline negative six degree decline
top speed of 12 miles per hour and
obviously you cannot forget that sled
push feature so this is obviously you
know great for your own individual goals
and it's going to allow you to switch up
your cardio workouts but this is also
great if you're looking for a treadmill
for the family everybody's going to have
their needs satisfied that being said
this is a very expensive treadmill 3 500
starting price tag
not everybody has the budget for that
and you know that's okay there's still
plenty of other treadmills out there
that are going to get the job done they
just don't have any to have as many
excuse me bells and whistles as this one
does right here and then also it's huge
you know it doesn't fold but also
it's at 40 incline so you at least need
to have ceilings that are eight feet
tall so those are things that could be
you know the main reason why you
wouldn't buy this treadmill
all right well that's all she wrote for
today's review over the NordicTrack
commercial x22i yes it's going to cost
you a pretty penny remember 3 500 and
yes it's going to dominate a good amount
of space but since it's so versatile I
really think it's worth every single
penny thanks for watching y'all I hope
this video was really helpful that I was
able to break down everything there is
to know about this treadmill as always
keep your eyes peeled for my next video
but for now head over to barbin.com
because we have a full written article
about this treadmill and I think you
should go and check that out all you got
to do is search bar Bend NordicTrack
commercial x22i review it's going to
pull right up for you you can go over
every single thing we talked about here
today now I'm gonna go get my cardio on
I'll catch y'all later
[Music]
thank you